[Music]
so
do
[Music]
so
hello good evening and good day
everybody welcome to the latest episode
of the ask a buddy show
today we are going to discuss a lot of
geopolitics and some other matters yes
in a current affairs and so on
it's going to be uh an interesting
session i think yeah so let us see who
all is here and let me greet you all i
can see joy deep i can see jay dixit
i can see uh
shaheen thank you so much sir
uh ishaan suraj nikhil
kuldeep
[Music]
thank you sir
and everyone else
thank you all for being here with me
this fine evening
and without further ado as always let's
get right into the questions so what are
the questions for today uh no big
surprise about question number one um
here we are
uh sure says is china going to attack
taiwan
the other question is can china defeat
the us akash says china didn't respond
to the pelosi visit of taiman taiwan
military do you think the worst is yet
to come in the future for taiwan and the
u.s any chances for world war three in
the future and dhiraj says how will
china respond and manage the strategic
and military competition with the us
after the pelosi visits to taiwan
and there's one more question related to
this ayush says i heard news that the
china attacked taiwan but mistakenly
dropped bombs in japan's ocean area
please uh
let's discuss what happened after nancy
pelosi visited taiwan and left within in
less than 24 hours right so these are
the questions right now about the taiwan
mata so let's take it one by one is
china going to attack thailand well the
option is there
if you're talking about military action
the option is open
china has a number of options at its
disposal right now it has a number of
cards that it can play
so is it going to attack thurman well i
don't have i am not privy to the mind of
mr xi jinping and the chinese communist
party politburo the option is available
yeah but then they have to do a risk
analysis cost benefit analysis what can
happen once you start a process you
can't reverse it right so uh
the option is there of china
launching military
action against taiwan the second
question is can china defeat the u.s if
the chinese were confident that they
could defeat the us then they would have
taken military action when nancy pelosi
was about to visit or yeah
and they had been threatening that they
would shoot down the plane or
accompanying fighter jets they did
nothing of the sort so if the chinese
thought that they could do it and get
away with it and defeat the us they
would certainly have done that but they
did not do it which indicates which
tells us very clearly that the chinese
know that it is not in their best
interests to start a shooting war with
the us kinetic warfare it's not going to
turn out well for them the us is
overwhelmingly more powerful than the
chinese that is a fact
china of course
has military advantages in the
uh champa samudra region the south
so-called south china sea region and in
the strait of taiwan etc so since we are
talking about this we must we must look
at the map where is the map the map is
here let me hide this for a second where
is the this this flash point
so
we know where india is yes so let's go
east of india we have the we have the
kalinga mahasagar which is apparently
called the bay of bengal we have the
champa samudra which is the south china
sea and here we have the island nation
avail yes
the island of taiwan right
and between taiwan and the chinese
mainland we have the
strait of thailand the taiwan strait
so this is where the entire matter is
happening now it's interesting to see
something
if you go to the city of xiamen the port
city of xiamen there is something called
the great kinman island this one here
kinman county yes
this
is administered by taiwan it's right off
the coast of china just a few
five or six kilometers off the coast of
china and it is administered by taiwan
so the chinese are okay with that you
see the chinese
know that eventually when the time is
read they can take everything back so
they are allowing the taiwanese to
control this little uh
island right off the coast of china
where they can actually see it
so this is the region we are talking
about right so what are the questions
once again let me see
uh
okay so the chinese i believe cannot
defeat the u.s it is extremely dangerous
for them to start any kind of military
action which involves the us they can
certainly dominate this region yes they
have a very powerful navy they may have
more numbers than the u.s has anywhere
in the world
the chinese navy is not
they don't have just a navy which means
the uh destroyers corvettes frigates
frigates submarines aircraft carriers
they also have
you know the chinese fishing fleet also
doubles up as a navy some of their other
vessels also which are typically
non-military vessels also have dual
purposes so they have a massive
numerical advantage in this region
like i keep saying repeatedly quantity
has a quality of its own india doesn't
seem to learn about this we are
investing in extremely expensive
platforms like aircraft carriers
quantity has a quality of its own it's
not my quote it's what joseph stalin
said okay when he was alive
this quote is attributed to joseph
stalin not to me but it's something i
use because it makes sense quantity has
a quality of its own the chinese have
been following this dictum
they have massive numbers of hulls
vessels in this region so if there is
warfare they could certainly take over
taiwan but then the long-term
consequences would be terrible
so uh so it's clear that the chinese
cannot
defeat the us it is not advantageous for
them to start military action
possibly yeah
uh
china does not did not respond to the
pelosi visit of taiwan militarily do you
think the worst is yet to come in the
future
and any chances for world war iii in the
future and this next question is also
similar to that right
right so
chances of world war three i hope are
remote
uh the thing about war is that it causes
a lot of destruction the us
and the chinese if they go to war china
will lose a lot of its infrastructure
they will lose
strategic assets so will the u.s and
wars can go beyond certain the wars can
cross certain lines that nobody wants
them to cross right uh when a certain
site feels threatened it may feel like
it is no option but but to use certain
weapons that we should not never ever
use
and both the chinese and the americans
have these weapons i'm talking about
nuclear weapons obviously
so
uh so
do i think the worst is yet to come in
the future let's talk about taiwan
what's happening in taiwan right now let
us take a look at what's happening in
taiwan so the chinese like i like i'd
say to somebody i'm not sure if i said
it here but i had said the chinese would
blockade taiwan straight they have
located not just the taiwan strait
they've located the entire island
they've located the entire island of
taiwan as you can see this is this image
it comes from chinese media okay so this
is their official uh
it's an image put out by the chinese
media itself uh government
media so they have all these different
uh
and and they call it military exercises
the chinese navy is
is engaging in legitimate military
exercises around the island of taiwan so
essentially what they've done is they
have completely blockaded
the island of taiwan they've imposed a
no-fly zone over taiwan which means that
no aircraft can come in no aircraft can
come out whether it is civilian aircraft
or military aircraft or government
aircraft or any such thing taiwan is now
cut off from the rest of the world
physically no aircraft are incoming or
outgoing and the taiwan is military
cannot take it do take any actual action
because they're completely surrounded
right now and as we know the chinese
fired
several uh ballistic missiles over
taiwan
right
so ballistic missiles have ballistic
trajectories they go out into they they
exit the atmosphere of the earth they go
into space and then they re-enter in a
parabolic trajectory so uh where did
these missiles uh so there was a
question about that as well
uh
china attacked taiwan but mistakenly
dropped bombs in japan's ocean area so
the chinese did not actually attack
taiwan but yes they launched cruise
missile sorry ballistic missiles over
the taiwan island so let's take a look
at the map and see where this happened
i'm not sure where the missiles
originated but somewhere across the
taiwan strait on the chinese mainland
and the missiles splashed down in this
region if you see this little island
here
hathiruma it belongs to japan as you can
see japan is right next door to taiwan
so this island
i believe is the southernmost uh region
in japan yeah southernmost point in
japan and the chinese ballistic missiles
splashed down
somewhere around this region in
japan's territorial waters in its
exclusive economic zone so the chinese
were sending not only a message to
taiwan but also to japan also to japan
china and japan have this long-standing
feud which dates back to the early 20th
century and maybe even before that so
that's a whole different story
uh china has grudges against everybody
essentially and their their their
objective is to teach everyone lesson
when the time is right so right now they
are saber rattling they
launched missiles that crossed the
taiwanese airspace of course in outer
space and they splashed down south of
japan this was not a mistake this was
very deliberately done it was a very
calculated move multiple i think it was
five ballistic missiles or maybe more
i'm not sure you can look it up the
exact numbers so that's what they have
been doing they have not actually
attacked taiwan militarily but yes they
are imposing a blockade and i don't see
this blockade ending anytime soon so
this is the new normal
this is currently the new normal uh the
the chinese have this very well-known
strategy or policy of
of creeping normalcy of salaam is
slicing encroaching one inch at a time
we know it very well we in india know it
very well they occupy
tibet currently
as of right now temporarily and from
tibet they have been engaging on all
these provocative maneuvers of of
grabbing half a meter of land one meter
300 meters somewhere here when no one is
looking because the terrain is very
mountainous in the india tibet border
region and so it's very easy to quickly
grab some land
so they have been doing this
with vis-a-vis india they were doing it
in the 1960s with the soviet union yeah
the chinese soviet union border clashes
the usuri river clashes in the 1960s
which nearly led to nuclear war so the
chinese are past masters at doing this
so what they are doing right now is
they are blockading taiwan and this i i
don't see this blockade ending
completely anytime soon
right this blockade is going to
this blockade
so
across the taiwan strait and into
taiwan's territorial
airspace taiwanese airspace and we
should also note that the taiwanese
air defense interdiction zone extends
into the into the chinese mainland so
that is something that the taiwan is
also uh they have also been doing
they've also been playing this game
right
so that is the situation that's what is
happening there
uh
so what are the other questions that we
have about this matter
uh how will china respond and manage the
strategic military competition with the
us after the pelosi visit to taiwan so
the main issue
for from the perspective of china
is not that taiwan is difficult to
capture it is
that taiwan essentially is a proxy of
the u.s right
when you're dealing with taiwan you're
essentially dealing with the u.s taiwan
is like a vasal state of the us they
they
it's like a u.s proxy it's like a u.s
held island in this
region uh there are these uh what you
call them the islands the island chains
first island chain second island train
so the first island chain is taiwan and
the japanese islands which kind of
cut off china's free access to the to
the pacific ocean
philippines is also kind of part of that
and then you have the second island
chain which is uh
um the marshall islands in guam and all
that which also the midway atoll etc
which are also held by the us so the
chinese feel that once they can
break free of these island chains then
they will have the freedom to
essentially take over the pacific ocean
region with their enormous naval
strength and so on but these islands are
very well defined and and starting any
military action will be extremely
counterproductive to china
so i think
that given the multiple options that
china has
the logical option is to continue an
aggressive policy of salami slicing
going to war they don't want to destroy
the island of taiwan right they want to
take it it's it's a valuable island it's
a it's a prize catch
if you destroy the island of taiwan in a
in a war in a ballistic war then you
will have to rebuild it they will have
to spend hundreds of millions of dollars
rebuilding the island of ireland it is
far more
it's far better to capture the island
entirely intact
that makes much more sense from a
military and strategic perspective from
a geopolitical perspective you don't
want to inherit a wasteland you want to
inherit something that is intact
so
what the chinese one of the options of
chinese have is to continue this
blockade of taiwan indefinitely just
keep it going on and on keep
encroaching into their airspace keep
encroaching into that naval naval space
uh that exclusive economic zone just
make it all irrelevant
make this the new normal that the
chinese will be everywhere and blockade
the island don't allow flights in and
out starvating to say it's it's a siege
policy siege warfare policy of of sorts
yes
and the chinese
uh
they have an enormous
economic clout there are certain
disaffected elements inside taiwan who
are politically more leaning towards the
chinese communist party there are always
such elements in any nation right there
are such anti-national elements in
russia
in china in taiwan
back home in india etc every nation has
certain such disaffected elements so in
taiwan there are certain uh elements
that support the chinese claim of real
chinese desire to reunify uh the island
of taiwan with the mainland
and the chinese
will
maybe financially support them and give
them more you know more prominence and
so that sort of thing could happen if
you are under a state of siege where you
are blockaded and you don't have any way
in or out then slowly over time you get
you get impatient and you start
resenting the government which is able
to do nothing and that's when these
other political forces gain more
currency and even the uh taiwanese uh
economy has a great deal of inter
linkages with china with the chinese
economy many of the companies work work
in both places etc so you could
influence the
taiwanese population through that as
well so that the chinese have multiple
means of achieving their long-term
objectives so i believe that right now
even though the military option is open
it is somewhat unlikely that the chinese
will indulge in a military
adventure or misadventure unlikely not
impossible yeah it is certainly on the
cards the cards are open but more likely
they will continue the blockade uh as
long as it takes they it it costs them
nothing they can keep on keep it going
they have a massive
naval uh strength and they will slowly
try to turn the tide internally in
taiwan and make the population more
receptive towards a reunification with
china and if there is an upsurge of the
sentiment then it becomes very hard for
even the americans
who keep on turning about democracy to
deny the sentiment so these are the the
options that the chinese have what they
will actually do remains to be seen
uh so so that's the situation as of
today right in this region
now let's take
a related question
don garcin johan says
why doesn't the us give nuclear weapons
to taiwan a state of deterrence might
prevent war interesting question
if you look at the u.s policies
over the past many many decades they
have nuclear weapons in various
parts of the world that are not their
directory first of all they have nukes
on submarines right nuclear weapons on
the moon they have a massive arsenal of
ballistic missiles uh that can deplo
that can deliver nuclear warheads to any
part of the world they also have nuclear
weapons in various parts of europe
right the uk which is a us colony or
wassal state
has a number of nuclear submarines that
have
british nuclear warheads mated to
american
i think it's the trident missile of the
polaris polaris is absolutely i believe
one of the one of the us ballistic
designs so i believe the launch codes
are not available with the uk prime
minister they are actually in the hands
of the americans so it's nukes only in
name
so the uk
has
american missiles mated to british uh
warheads
so you can say it's it's essentially
american nukes that the uk nominally has
then i believe that in the netherlands
and in turkey as well there are american
nuclear missiles deployed there
so they are not in the hands of the
local governments they are entirely
under the control of the u.s military
and the u.s government but they have
been deployed in these places i think
it's the netherlands possibly belgium
turkey for sure and so on
so
the americans do that
but they don't give that nation the the
control over those weapons so what about
taiwan let's go back to the map because
it makes sense to look at the map so we
have taiwan here
let's say the americans uh place nuclear
missiles in taiwan
in order to let's say uh
deter chinese aggression right
is it not possible that the taiwanese if
if they are if they are
put under a state of siege for months
maybe two years three years they may get
fed up and they may open the gates for
the chinese to come in and then those
nukes may fall into the chinese hands
and they will have access to american
nuclear weapons technology and missile
technology is it that is it not possible
is it not possible that you might have
chinese spies on taiwanese territory
that might possibly try to leak out
certain secrets
if taiwan falls for whatever reason
those nukes those missiles will
immediately go into the hand of the of
the chinese
when the americans did this uh attack
this uh attack on uh this operation
in abortabad to take out apparently
osama bin laden one of their helicopters
malfunctioned there to destroy it and
then the pakistanis handed over the
remains of the helicopter to the chinese
this was a secret helicopter it was a
classified helicopter whose existence
had not yet been disclosed to the public
right so there was some advanced
technology there were certain advanced
technologies in the helicopter some
stealth
technologies some some coating material
which would uh radar absorbent material
and various other things as well so
whatever was left of the helicopter they
had to destroy the helicopter in a great
haste they put some plastic explosive or
whatever some charges and they blew it
up but
much of it still remained intact it was
no longer functional
but you could study it very well it's
not like the brahmos missile that went
into pakistan and was completely mangled
out of shape nothing left left of it the
pakistanis could not glean any
information or technology from it the
helicopter had some valuable technology
and the chinese took that so we don't
want the americans do not want such
things to happen again so far away from
our american control taiwan
is a fortress surrounded by the wolves
essentially when it comes to europe
western europe is entirely under us
control so it's perfectly safe to place
american nuclear weapons and missiles in
western europe in the netherlands in in
the uk
even turkey is greatly dependent on the
americans the middle east is entirely
essentially under american control so is
egypt so is north africa so is the
mediterranean region so it is safe to
deploy american uh nuclear weapons and
missiles on turkish territory when it
comes to taiwan it is an extremely
hostile territory it is not safe for the
americans to place their extremely
sensitive technologies and weapons over
here so i believe that is the reason why
the americans have never done this and
of course that would provoke china
incredibly to an incredible extent uh if
you place nuclear weapons there but
don't disclose it then
this the
entire purpose of deterrence doesn't
happen
but if you place nuclear weapons there
and
and and you disclose that that is going
to be seen as an extremely grave
provocation almost like a declaration of
war by the chinese and then there will
be consequences of at various
levels at various orders of magnitude
then it will be legitimate for the
chinese to to uh to escalate to ratchet
up their tensions in north korea
start something there because north
korea is controlled by controlled by the
chinese they could escalate matters with
the japanese in the in the senkaku the
iu islands etc they could do all kinds
of things and the americans most likely
don't want things to escalate that far
they want a controlled escalation
eventually they want a bifurcation of
the world order a bipolar world china
and iran and russia on one side and the
americans and the other nations on the
other side bipolar world
the chinese want a unipolar world india
russia
france etc want a multiple world so that
is the the the game that is being played
right now right so that in short is the
reason why the americans have not given
nuclear weapons to the taiwanese
okay harsh says doesn't attacking india
before attacking taiwan make more sense
for china
that is an interesting thought
so right now what's happened
is that before nancy pelosi visited
taiwan the chinese made a lot of noise
did a lot of saber rattling a lot of
strong words we will shoot down the
aircraft and you are
you your crossing over red lines and
final warning and all that yes
but then the visit happened the
americans called the chinese bluff
and the chinese were able to do nothing
they just sat and watched she came
over there under their noses she did
whatever she was she wanted to do and
then she left
so that
is a loss of face
that is a public humiliation
right that is indeed you cannot put it
in any other way the chinese have been
publicly humiliated
their threats have been shown to be
empty
yeah
and we have to understand we have to
remember that
in in autumn
this year
mr xi jinping is due to be re-elected
re-selected reappointed as the supreme
leader of china
yeah so that is a critical
uh uh critical event a very high stakes
event for mr xi jinping and for the
chinese leadership
now if a leader of mr xi jinping's
stature
is publicly humiliated if he loses face
yeah then he will lose credibility and
will become
difficult for him to become to be
reappointed yeah you could there is a
lot of internal
politics in the chinese communist party
it's a very
dog-eat-dog world
yeah it's a it's a cutthroat environment
the
the people who rise to the top in the
chinese communist party do that at the
expense of lots of others
mr xi jinping has left a lot of people
in his wake
and during his rise to the top yeah he
has
gone he in the initial phase of his
leadership he once he became the supreme
leader he had launched this war on
corruption in which he destroyed a lot
of his
uh political rivals
so
any leader who reaches that position
within the chinese communist party will
have a lot of enemies
as long as the leader is
is is strong and is performing well
the
descent
will be kept under the carpet but once
some kind of public humiliation happens
and a loss of face happens there are
going there's going to be trouble
right
knives are going to be sharpened
so
what's happening i think it's october
this
re-election re-selection reappointment
that entire procedure that is extremely
important for mr xi jinping so right now
what's happened to him is a humiliation
and people on chinese social media have
they've taken to chinese social media
and expressed their their frustration
and their anguish and all that at what
the americans have been able to pull off
yeah it makes the chinese communist
party look weak it makes the leader look
weak which is very dangerous for the
leader and also for the chinese
communist party the chinese communist
party is
they have this unspoken unwritten social
contract with the chinese people that
you will accept our dictatorship and we
will make china great in return for you
and we will improve your standards of
living and all that and it is all built
on a plank of hyper nationalism that
china is the middle kingdom the greatest
nation on earth we're going to outpace
the americans we're going to replace and
displace the americans as the global
superpower and so on
that is the promise that has been made
to the chinese people repeatedly again
and again through every single
pronouncement by the chinese government
and now when this happens
that
is extremely dangerous for the cc for
the ccp and for mr xi jinping so mr
jinbing
right now is treading dangerous waters
if he loses credibility the chinese
communist party will quietly replace him
his career will be over once you fall
from that position you're done
in multiple ways
so if mr xi jinping loses credibility if
he does not show the chinese people
again that i am i am the i'm the guy i'm
the man i'm the big and the person who
can take china forward
then he will be there could be coup in
china so i have this podcast with dr
edward luthwalk on this channel you can
look at we can look it up in which we
have discussed this matter that is mr xi
jinping's position secure in china and
how could a coup against special xi
jinping happen within the chinese
communist party and he has spoken about
that so this sort of thing could happen
if mr xi jin they will if things go
wrong the chinese communist party will
blame the leader and they will put all
the blame on him they will scapegoat him
get rid of him and get somebody else in
his place that is a very real
possibility and right now that
possibility is no longer a hypothetical
or theoretical possibility
people are actively considering that i
am sure within the chinese communist
party very dangerous time so mr xi
jinping
so what can mr xi jinping do about this
after all this big talk
nothing happened so the first thing is
like we know the chinese are blockading
taiwan
but is that enough to avenge the
humiliation blockading taiwan or does
china need to show something more
in order to restore the prestige and the
credibility of mr xi jinping
that is why
the option of some kind of misadventure
with india
is open so if
mr xi jinping
or all the chinese leadership calculates
that they can get away with some kind of
short sharp war with india in which
india loses more territory then the
chinese public could be placated yes yes
yes we are back we are back we have done
it we have shown it you know so that
option is always open and obviously uh
the the
the chinese uh do not want a strong
government in india if india loses a
short sharp war with the chinese in
which they are publicly in which india
is humiliated by losing more territory
then it could conceivably lead to
the fall of the government in the next
elections 2024
so the chinese could end up uh killing
two birds with one stone they could mr
xi jinping could restore his lost
prestige and they could also engineer a
fall of the current indian government
led by mr modi right and then there
could be some coalition government in
india with all the all those regional
parties that do nothing and then then
then india would be much more amenable
to chinese colonization and chinese
whatever the chinese want which was the
case in the past
right
so that is a very uh
attractive
option in my opinion for the chinese the
question is according to chinese
calculations is it worth the risk
is it worth the risk one would imagine
that the chinese if they were to
start something with india they would do
it in the sikkim siliguri corridor
region
and they would want to if they can take
over the siliguri corridor region then
that would cut off these the far east of
india
from indian control and that would be a
massive humiliation for india
so that is typically where they would go
or they would go into encroaching
further into the ladakh region or
whatever
or in arunachal pradesh so these are
various options the chinese have they
are always actively considering this the
question is do they believe
that they can get away with it
because i know
i can guarantee that the indian
government is also very much aware of
the options that the chinese have and
the fact that right now mr xi jinping is
kind of desperate to restore his
credibility and he could be tempted to
do something with this
so i believe that india is very much
aware of what the chinese are doing the
chinese could go into bhutan possibly
but that is not a big enough thing for
them they want to uh
throw a few punches at a much bigger
actor geopolitical actor so india is a
good option for that
i believe the indian military and the
indian government is very much aware of
all this that the chinese could do such
a thing and they would have already war
gamed all the possible scenarios and we
have spoken about this in detail the
chinese positions in tibet are pretty
much exposed
india has satellites and other assets in
in place which can monitor chinese
activities in
real time essentially even at night
and if the chinese do anything if they
their military bases and their camps and
all are within easy reach of indian
of of indian missiles and aircraft and
all that
india has multiple advantages and of
course the chinese know that they cannot
go too far with a nuclear armed nation
otherwise they're going to
lose much more than they will gain
so this is a balancing act there is
going to be the temptation for the
chinese leadership and mr xi jinping
especially given the events in taiwan
last week
this temptation will be there to
possibly restore some kind of some some
kind of credibility by attacking india
and
taking a bite out of indian territory
then the humiliation that suffered at
the hands of the us will be temporarily
forgotten and the mission can go ahead
and get reelected or re-select or
re-appointed
in the next
in that
october or in the autumn session right
so it does make kind of sense for china
to consider this very seriously
attacking india before taiwan
maybe they don't want to attack seven at
all they want to take over the island
without firing a single shot slowly over
time
blockade the island and eventually
engineer an internal takeover of the
nation of the island but visa with india
there is always the temptation for china
to attack india to make a point to their
own people foreign policy is a
reflection of internal politics always
whether it's the us whether it is india
whether it is other nations whether it
is france whether it is china whether it
is russia foreign policy is always a
reflection of internal affairs and
internal
you know
whatever is going on inside if you need
to appease your people you need to do
certain things in the foreign policy
domain which will kind of make the
people happy that these calculations are
always there
so yes we are going through a kind of a
dangerous time right now what's
happening in taiwan could have
repercussions in other parts of asia and
other parts of the world and india
obviously needs to be very alert and be
aware of the fact that the chinese could
have such such
intentions or motivations
ac says
why does the republic of china taiwan
still claim the same parts of india as
the people's republic of china does even
after 73 years of being exiled to the
island why haven't we been able to make
taiwan drop their claims to excite you
in some parts of pakistan occupied
kashmir arunachal pradesh et cetera and
why haven't they done this themselves
please understand my dear friends that
taiwan is a u.s muslim state
taiwanese foreign policy is essentially
u.s foreign policy
taiwan is a u.s puppet
a sock puppet
so whatever the taiwanese do is a
reflection of what the u.s wants
understand this things are not what they
appear on the surface
if you want to truly understand
geopolitics if you want to truly
understand history current affairs you
have to look below the surface
appearances are always deceptive
you can watch news 24 hours a day you
will learn nothing
you have to go deeper
you know in chess
a grandmaster thinks 15 steps ahead a
regular person like me and you will will
think maybe two step side or three steps
ahead a grandmaster is able to think 15
steps ahead if you want to understand
things you have to be able to look
beneath the surface of things you to
understand what really happened what is
the history what are the
interconnections what are the systems
and things like that
right so taiwan whether you like it or
not no there is no other way of saying
it beyond saying that taiwan is a u.s
vassal state taiwan is foreign policy is
an extension of american foreign policy
right
and of course there are certain internal
matters as well which which the u.s will
accommodate as far as it doesn't really
make too much of a difference to their
national interests
so yes the taiwanese government claims
tibet as part of their country they
claim arunachal pradesh they claim
parts of pakistan occupied jammu and
kashmir yeah and and so on so forth
aksai chain as well
they claim that
and in the past it's it's so happened
that the president of five and that lady
i forget her name she on twitter wished
india in a happy independence day etc
and like all other world leaders do and
mr modi our prime minister responded to
all the other world leaders but he did
not respond to the wishes
to the tweet of the taiwan taiwan is uh
leader
president right
so they and and people and indian
commentators indian geopolitical
commendators etc we're urging mr modi mr
modi please respond to this friendly
gesture from taiwan etc and so on
mr moly did not do that there are good
reasons for that you have to understand
that most people don't even know that
taiwan has the same claims on indian
territory as the chinese communist party
does
taiwan cannot be regarded as a friendly
nation to india
if they have these claims it means they
are claiming our territory which has
been our territory for thousands of
years
yeah
so that is not a friendly the the
behavior of a friend
right
so yeah
so the reason why it is so is first of
all because they themselves have an
expansionist mindset and secondly
because the americans want to keep
pressurizing india by having these
tactics
and taiwanese foreign policy is an
extension of american foreign policy
taiwan is an instrument in the hands of
america to deal with to deal with china
to uh
to control
this region which region the the the
west pacific region
the so-called south china sea east china
sea region and all that
so that's what it is
okay edgelord says
the problem with xi jin the problem is
xi jinping and some psychos in top
positions of the ccp chinese communist
party if the chinese communist party
reforms and ends hostility towards other
countries then india and china can
easily become friends and form an asian
union
um psychos
i think the top leadership of the
chinese communist party is extremely
realistic
it's very pragmatic very practical
and um
they are
very logical they're not psychos
and if you look at the history of china
china and if you look at the kind of
leaders they've had in the past
i think mr xi jinping is a reasonably
well balanced person
yeah
all you have to do the problem is we
don't study history right we don't study
history just go back a few decades and
see what kind of leaders they have
see what mr mao zedong did to the to his
own people
nearly a hundred million deaths in china
and wars with everybody
yeah
i think mr xi jinping if you will
compare him with mr mao zedong is a
extremely moderate and well balanced
person the overall objectives of the
chinese communist party have never
changed
their overall objective from day one
has always been consistent and the same
to expand
in all directions take over everybody's
territory and become the
center of the of the world
middle kingdom
the only nation that matters everybody
else is irrelevant that's always been
the aim the dream the hope
of the chinese communist party so mr xi
jinping is doing the same thing that his
predecessors were doing
and right now he is
in
he has the advantage of a massive
economy and a massive military
because he's a massive military he's
able to pour so much more money into the
military
even if the chinese are spending the
same percentage of the gdp on on
as india on the military they are able
to uh have a military budget of maybe
150 billion dollars or maybe 200 billion
dollars somewhere there
right because the economy is so much
more massive i don't think these people
are psychos
i think if mr xi jinping falls by the
wayside and somebody else comes to power
that person may be even worse way worse
than mr xi jinping it is a possibility
right now
he has kind of lost face he has been
kind of humiliated by the americans if
he loses his position as the as
the boss as the supreme leader of the
ccp and somebody else is put in place
by the ccp that person is going to is is
likely to be much more of a hard liner
than mr xi jinping is
so uh the sh the ccp is not going to
reform
they are not going to end their
hostility towards india or other nations
they even covet
russian territory that that claim has
never really gone away
if you look at the this region of
manchuria the osuri river and all that
they claim this territory they have
dormant claims to this territory and
those claims will be reactivated when
the time is right
so the ccp is not going to reform
it is the one thing that gives them
legitimacy in the eyes of the public in
the eyes of 1.4 billion chinese that the
ccp is the only is is going to make us
great it's going to make china number
one it's going to transform china into a
superpower and we will be the most
prestigious and greatest people in the
world
that is the social contract that is the
promise and that is why the ccp is in
power
the moment they lose their credibility
there's going to be civil war in china
that is
a process it's a cycle you see over and
over and over again in chinese history
the dynastic cycles
the ccp is just one dynasty so we need
to be realistic the ccp is not going to
reform if they start reforming and
becoming more moderate they will lose
credibility in the eyes of their own
people and that will lead to the
downfall
they cannot afford that to happen
chinese civil wars are never pretty
they are extraordinarily massive messy
and bloody so
india needs to be extremely realistic
and hard-nosed there is no possibility
of china ending its hostility towards
india there is no possibility of having
a friendly asian union there could be
cooperation between india and china if
india rises rapidly in the next 10 years
and becomes a significant economy and a
significant military power the chinese
will have no option but to
grudgingly
shake hands with india and cooperate on
a variety of matters but the overall
objective long-term objective will still
be the same to destroy india and become
number one
so i have said in the past there is a
possibility in the future of cooperation
between india and china i have not said
there will be friendship and warmth
there will be issue based cooperation
which which already exists between india
and china but always remember the
objective of the chinese communist party
is to make china the
sole
superpower in the world
and a strong india united india
does not figure
in their
future envisioned world order all right
so that's the daily
okay a couple of questions uh samarth
gandhi says why did sri lanka allow
chinese nuclear missile tracking ship to
dock
how should india deal with this should
india stop helping sri lanka knowledge
seeker says why are we so weak that a
rival nation can send its military ship
to a port of our neighboring country
close to our nation and we are just
angry with the neighboring nation which
is kind of like betraying us even after
giving aid
why are we or our government so
unwilling to address this issue
intelligently all right
so
uh the chinese
want to send a missile tracking ship a
spy ship electronic measures ship etc
signals electronic signals tracking ship
to sri lanka to the
port let's see where it is
they want to send it there they have not
sent it there yet they have not uh
docked the ship there
so where is hamantata somewhere in the
south of the country where is it where
is it here it is this is hambantota
this is a port that is essentially owned
by the chinese
you know given a bit of the chinese but
the previous corrupt syrian sri lankan
government
all sri lankan governments are more or
less corrupt essentially
so right now sri lanka is going through
a crisis india is helping sri lanka
india is providing a
long and massive line of credit in india
sending various uh i mean i mean you
know food grains etc or maybe diesel
petrol whatever to sri lanka to help
them tide over this crisis there's a new
government that's coming to place uh
ranil vikkar messing is the new
new leader in sri lanka he is another
stooge of the west if you look at his
history you will know that i will not go
to the details right now
so the chinese
want to send a spy ship electronic
tracking ship to to sri lanka
and this ship is is extremely
sophisticated very good technology it
can track
missile launches and rocket launches
very precisely
so let's say india wants to launch some
kind of
ship is sorry not ship rocket let's say
isro wants to to launch some rocket
israel launches a rocket this ship can
track it from very far away from all the
way south in the southern part of sri
lanka
the israel launching place is somewhere
in orissa right right
vishaka but um somewhere in this region
somewhere in the eastern part of india
orissa
a few
hundred maybe a few thousand kilometers
from ahmada so the chinese through this
ship will be able to track that rocket
launch let's say we are launching a new
kind of rocket which we did today a tiny
rocket so the chinese if they have a
ship in this region they can track it
and they can kind of decode
what this rocket is about what is new
about it what is different about it what
are the capabilities the new
capabilities that the indians have
acquired or or built
similarly
if india is to launch
a ballistic missile
an intercontinental or
intermediate-range ballistic missile
from the eastern coast of india
then this chinese ship in sri lanka will
be able to track it
and monitor the missile launch
and give the chinese a great deal of
very
good intelligence
about the characteristics and parameters
and capabilities and range
of the new ballistic missiles that india
is testing
so that is what the chinese are doing
that's so they have requested the sri
lankans
to say to allow this chinese spy ship to
dock in the hambantota port initially
the sri lankan government agreed to this
and that's why there was this uproar in
indian media
the latest thing i've heard is that the
sri lankans have said we are giving you
permission but after so and so date
so i don't know what the date is and i
don't know if there is some event coming
up in india
around that date so the sri lankans are
giving permission but after a certain
date
i'm sure the indian ministry of foreign
affairs is in constant contact with the
sri lankans
and india would have made certain things
clear to sri lanka
so yeah so there is a situation right
now they have been given permission to
dock but after a certain date and maybe
there's something coming up in india
some kind of missile launch or some test
or something which i am not quite sure
what it is but it may be there there
could be something coming up
uh
so that's the deal now the question is
how should india deal with this india
should make it very clear to sri lanka
that this sort of behavior is not
acceptable
that's for sure
should india stop helping sri lanka you
see in international affairs in
geopolitics all help is conditional
like i've said many times there are no
friendships
in geopolitics the indian government has
a singular purpose to serve
the nation and its people
and to further india's national interest
that is the only purpose of the indian
government indian money whatever it is
the government has at its disposal is to
be used for these purposes only
now if india is giving aid to sri lanka
financial aid monetary aid other aid
there has to be some reciprocity it has
to be conditional aid the aid we are
giving to a foreign nation
sri lanka is currently a foreign nation
for now it's a separate country it's a
separate government and separate people
so if we are giving aid to sri lanka it
has to have certain conditions that you
will not do this or that or whatever
there has to be very clear conditions
and in case the sri lanka so in the in
case the sri lankans are
doing
or taking actions or steps that are
detrimental to india's national interest
the aid should be immediately cut off
and there should be further
action
which could
essentially ensure that sri lanka
doesn't indulge in such activities again
right
um
so is sri lanka betraying us no they are
not betraying us they are testing us
there are no betrayals in geopolitics
there are u-turns and you the public can
consider that to be betrayal but
actually it is nothing but a standard
geopolitical maneuver
yeah a so-called betrayal the sri
lankans are testing the limits of where
they can go vis-a-vis india they are
currently dependent on india india is
giving them all this aid they still want
to see how far they can go without uh
before the indians get upset and and
they they stop the sri lankans so they
are testing india
the government that is currently in
power is is this guy vikrama singh is a
western stooge he is a member of various
well
organizations that will
demonstrate his credentials as a as a
time tested western stooge so that's
what the
sri lankans are doing now the thing
about i can understand why people get
upset uh people get upset that india is
helping another nation and india is
getting nothing in return they are
betraying us
india our india is india
is india not intelligent
is india helpless why are we helping
people for nothing uh
the thing is this india is still india
is now definitely emerging as a major
geopolitical power and yet
india is not able to control certain
countries in its neighborhood sri lanka
is now coming to hill for sure but there
are other nations in india's
neighborhood that india is still not
able to influence to the extent that it
would like to influence the question you
have to ask yourselves is this
let's take a look at the indian
territory yes
let's remove this
this is the geographical extent of the
present-day nation state of india
how many portions within india's
territorial boundaries
is the indian government able to control
completely
there are certain regions
where
there are problems
there are problems there are so many see
people talk about a 2.5 front war what
they mean is that
india's main enemies are within india
there are so many uh
actors
let's say
within india's own territory that are on
the payroll of foreign governments and
who are serving the national interests
of other nations
this is known to everyone
and we know the nations that are
funding these various actors and
elements within indian territory
a nation like india or any other nation
can become geopolitically influential
only when it deals with the internal
threats first
right
take a look at china why is china so
influential in its neighborhood because
they have quelled all internal
problems
there are lots of
uh elements let's say within china that
would like to see china as in its
present state to be broken up
and there are legitimate interests when
we talk about tibet tibet doesn't belong
in china when you talk about manchuria
you may not know this but manchuria
should not be chinese territory the the
chinese have taken over half of mongolia
so there are many forces within china
that would legitimately like to see the
chinese nation broken up because it's
taken over so many foreign territories
but the chinese have quelled all that
internal descent there is
the writ of the chinese communist party
is supreme
within the chinese territory and that's
why they're able to be so influential
externally when it comes to russia there
are lots of these western stooges within
russia
i will not take names but there are such
people those have been let's say
their their actions have been kind of
neutralized by the russian government
you can call it despotism dictatorship
whatever you want to call it i don't
care
but practically they have been able
to neutralize those foreign forces
within russia and that's why russia is
so geopolitically influential externally
the u.s
it doesn't tolerate dissent
internally
it talks about democracy and human
rights and freedom of expression and all
that but anybody who speaks who takes
actions that are detrimental to u.s
national interests within the nation
will be immediately dealt with
extraordinarily harshly
so you have to first
take complete control of your own
territory
and quell all anti-national elements and
forces
once you do that
you will automatically become powerful
geopolitically so india has a lot of
internal friction
internal problems
once that is dealt with
when everybody is on board with the
national interest right now lots and
lots of forces within india are working
against india's national interests
once that is dealt with india will
automatically
be
orders of magnitude 10 times 100 times
more influential than it is right now so
that is the real
problem that we are facing
in india right
so that's the deal with the chinese spy
ship in sri lanka
luis
if india assists
if india assists the chinese the the
the shanghai organization meet if india
attends the shanghai organization
meetings at the same time it forms part
of the aukus australia uk us or the quad
where does that leave it in the case of
a possible near future war on the taiwan
strait even if limited greetings from
mexico greetings from india sir so uh
india is indeed part of the shanghai
cooperation
organization seo yeah which is
essentially a chinese creature it's it's
been created by the chinese russia is
part of india as part of it pakistan is
part of it and several
central asian nations are part of the
sco india is
one of the major nations there are three
major nations india china and russia it
is china dominated right
so india is part of the seo india is
also part of the quad which the chinese
construe as an anti-china alliance so
the core it's not an alliance as such
it's a coalition it's india and america
and its puppet states it's india the us
australia and japan
australia and japan are u.s colonies
essentially so it's an indo-us coalition
of sorts and the chinese consider that
to be an anti-china alliance
so on the one hand india is cooperating
with china in the seo it is part of the
same organization on the other hand it
is part of an organization that is
rightly or wrongly construed by china as
an anti-china organization right
so this is what i spoke about in the
past about the what what we call the
jaishankar doctrine that india will
engage with all major geopolitical
players
in in issue-based cooperation
there will be complete broad spectrum
cooperation when it comes to economic
development
activities
yeah
with the us with china with the west but
there will be issue based cooperation
on
strategic matters on geopolitical
matters on foreign policy matters
and there will be no cooperation it when
it comes to things that can impact
india's national interest which is why
when it comes to china there is not that
much of economic cooperation because the
china the chinese want to flood india
with their cheap products and extract
money out of india so that's why india
is not engaging economically also that
much with china but it is
part of the seo visa with the central
asian region and
these other nations so india is
giving issue based cooperation to
various nations even even to the chinese
depending on what uh what issue we are
dealing with
which tells you that india is pursuing a
policy of multi-alignment this is not
non-alignment this is multi-alignment
this is a complete break from the past
in the past india was part of the losers
club the non-aligned nations and the
objective was to achieve nothing
yeah there were there was no real
geopolitical or geo-economic objective
that the nam
had
so
today india is following a very
different foreign policy india is for
pursuing a foreign policy of
furthering its national interest by
cooperating with whoever
has mutual uh
in ways that are mutually beneficial
with a wide range of of nations
so the question so that is the context
to this question now the question is
where does it leave india in the case of
a possible
near future war on the taiwan strait
even if limited india will say it's none
of our business
india will say we don't have a horse in
this race
it this does not concern india we call
upon the the warring parties to cease
fire immediately and stop hostilities
and please ensure that civilians are not
affected and not hurt
that's what india will say
exactly what india said in the ukraine
war
india called upon
both nations
to uh have ceasefire to have a ceasefire
to ensure that civilians are not
affected and so on and so forth yes
and uh
anytime civilians were killed or
whatever india condemned that etc
but india has not taken sides india has
condemned the military action india has
called for a cease for ceasefire india
has called for a negotiated settlement
diplomatic settlement instead of
military settlement but india has the
refrain from taking sides and india has
refrained from condemning
either of the
either of the nations explicitly
right whether it's ukraine whether it's
russia similarly if there is a conflict
in the taiwan state india will
india will repeat this procedure india
will
will call
for a military ceasefire india will call
for a cessation of hostilities
india
will call for a negotiated diplomatic
solution of the problem
and india will
demand that civilians are not targeted
in i in any manner
this is what india will do but india
will refrain most likely from condemning
any side and india will refrain from
getting involved in any way whatsoever
but of course india will monitor the
situation very closely
and and in case certain advantages
conditions arise in certain ways india
will certainly take advantage of that as
any nation would
so that is how i see things going in the
hypothetical scenario of a future
war in the taiwan state if the war goes
beyond the taiwan trade and becomes a
widespread war as wars
tend to do sometimes remember 1914 so if
that happens in india will take
appropriate measures to defend its
national interest and and other
interests
so that's how i see
that's what i see happening right
samad says why is the u.s delaying
nuclear missile tests
so the tests we are talking about are
the americans were supposed to test out
the periodic tests they conduct
on their ballistic missiles
these are nuclear capable ballistic
missiles but they're not testing a
nuclear weapon they're testing that the
missile works properly so let's take a
look at the map and now let me tell you
what this missile test was supposed to
be about
uh let's go to the u.s
west coast
so uh north west of los angeles
northwest of santa barbara the americans
of the vandenberg air force base do you
see this
this place is called the vandenberg air
force base this is from where the
missile test was supposed to happen the
it's an intercontinental ballistic
missile around eight thousand nine
thousand ten thousand kilometers range
maybe more maybe more
um
this is called the missile is called a
minuteman iii missile it was supposed to
be launched from there and it was
supposed to go go into the region of the
mariana islands
the mariana islands in this region
so if we take a look at the distance
let's calculate the distance from here
measure distance from here all the way
to wendenberg air force base
somewhere in this region
the distance is around 9000 kilometers
so you can see it's an intercontinental
ballistic missile range
the minutemen iii missile and every
nation that has such missiles
conducts periodic tests of these
missiles to see that they are working
fine right
so this test was supposed to happen
earlier in the year
but then the the the russian
intervention in ukraine happened so the
americans delayed the test they said
let's uh not not
indulge in any provocating provocating
uh maneuvering so they delayed the test
they said let things settle down a
little bit now they were supposed to
have this test around this time i
believe
and because of the taiwan straight
crisis they've again delayed the test so
as to not offend china and and
you know
keep tensions low so that is the
official thing that i'm hearing
they are delaying or deferring the
missile test in order to keep the
tensions low there are already enough
tension in the taiwan region etc they
don't want to add fuel to that fire
apparently that's what they are saying
now i don't see how a missile test far
away from china
a routine missile test far far away from
china would would add to the tensions
with china
or even with russia when you're testing
a missile in the pacific ocean right the
mariana islands are far away from china
if you if you look at the map where's
the map here's the map
the mariana islands are the second
island island chain they are way way way
far away from china
right so i don't see how it should
offend china or or
make them
you know
or add to the tensions but that is what
the americans have said that's the i
think that's been the official
communication or response to questions
so that's what they have said now does
it make sense to me it doesn't really
make much sense to me but
yeah well i'm sure they know things that
i i don't know right i'm just an outside
observer there is an even horizon i
don't know what's beyond the event
horizon i'm trying to guess deduce
prognosticate based on whatever evidence
is available outside
so that's what they have said they don't
want to add to the tensions that are
currently
existing visa with taiwan and that's why
they are delaying it yeah that's it
alpha beta says why the hell
does dw knew okay why has dw news
started to criticize mr ukraine mr
zelinski
what's the reason
yes we are observing certain strange
phenomena in the geopolitical sphere in
the journalistic sphere media you know
uh
the western controlled media is kind of
criticizing mr zielinski
i have not seen this dw news thing but
like you're saying it must have happened
but what i can show you is this
we all know amnesty international which
is controlled by the by the west which
means it is controlled by the us they
are always critical of india
if you see their twitter let me show you
an interesting tweet from amnesty
international which came uh three days
ago august 4th
they said this
ukrainian forces have put civilians in
harm's way by establishing bases and
operating weapon systems in populated
residential areas such tactics violate
international humanitarian law and
endanger civilians as they turn civilian
objects into military targets
now in case you have seen my previous
episodes from when the year russia
ukraine was started i said precisely the
same things
i said that the ukrainians are are using
these horrible tactics of putting the
you know weapon systems etc in civilian
areas
and when the russians are forced to
retaliate it will cause civilian
casualties it will make the russians
look bad but the ukrainians are putting
their civilians on the line as cannon
fodder i said that this thing in
february in march and i got a lot of
criticism for that
lots of
western commentators i saw the comments
they're still there on my channel i in
the the comments that they put
now amnesty international is
corroborating what i had said at that
time
right
now so what's happening
amnesty international
is
essentially an agent of the west
of the western powers which means the
u.s they are used time and against to
criticize the indian government to make
india look bad to claim that india has
human rights abuses and god knows what
else all lies
so how come they have suddenly turned
against mr zielinski in the ukraine
regime
what's what's happening and like uh mr
alfa beta says or who he or she is yeah
i don't know the gender so apparently dw
news also is criticizing mr ukraine mr
zelinski and maybe some other things may
also be up up there in the media i
haven't seen yet yeah
this is an interesting turn of events is
the tide turning for mr zelinski is he
no longer
of much use to the west have has it
served his purpose
if things continue like this you may
soon in the forthcoming days see stories
of mr zelinski's half billion dollars in
some bank account in the west or
something like that
and then
all they have to do is put all the blame
on him that he mismanaged the situation
and that's why ukraine is not doing well
that's why ukraine is losing blame it
all on him and then
move on
so you see it's like this
whether it was mr saddam hussein whether
it was anybody else the west uses
these despotic people these little
puppet puppet-like people sadamasan
actually was a
iraqi nationalist he tried to take his
country in a certain direction he was
not a puppet
but yes he he was certainly an agent of
the u.s for a long time the americans
used saddam hussein as the
as a stick to beat iran with
and then when he served his powers and
threw him to the wolves we know what
they did to him they the americans have
this
history
if you study the history of the 20th
century in africa in other places they
have this history of doing this again
and again and again propping somebody up
as long as they serve a certain purpose
and then once the purpose is served you
throw that person to the wolves so it
looks like
it looks like mr zelensky is a kind of
in trouble if amnesty internationally
criticizes him openly and doesn't delete
the tweet the tweet is there for three
days it sends a certain signal
it looks like mr zelensky's days
as as a world leader
are numbered
yeah so i don't know what's going on
maybe the americans are now
they want to focus more on the taiwan
thing
yeah the ukraine russia thing is old
news now tire that people are tired you
know these wars are distractions for the
american public to keep the public
engaged on things that are apparently
very important
there is a recession there is a terrible
recession happening in the u.s right now
the us government has changed the
definition of recession in order to
claim there is no recession the
definition of recession ask any
economist is
two or more quarters of negative gdp
growth
what's a quarter three months
there are four quarters in a year the
first three months the next three months
the next three months the next month
the definition
of a recession in economics is two
consecutive quarters
of negative economic growth
of gdp getting smaller
and that's what's happening in the u.s
the u.s is in a recession
the fuel prices are are
extraordinarily high right now
just see what the prices of of gasoline
or fuel where during donald trump's time
and see what the prices are right now
during the time during the presidency of
joe biden
look at the approval ratings of joe
biden the lowest in all u.s history
yeah lower than jimmy carter
so there are problems internally
yeah now ukraine was a nice diversion
for the american public we are doing
something righteous we are supporting
the righteous side we are supporting
zelensky this great freedom fighter now
people may be getting tired of it
so let's start something new in taiwan
we send pillows there to stir up the
flames and now let's focus on taiwan i'm
just speculating i don't know what the
decision making and thought process is
in the state department in the us
government etc but this is what it looks
like so maybe now
the tide may turn for mr zelinsky now
the western media is is
allowed to criticize him rightly for
what he's doing and it's not he who's
doing that he's just the the face the
public face of the ukrainian government
right
he doesn't really have any power he's
just an actor who's acting as president
he and his wife they had this recent
photo shoot
on on the front page of vogue as you may
have seen so that's what's going on
so the see the tide seems to be turning
for mr zelinski it looks like he may not
no longer be of a great deal of use
for the puppet masters who are running
ukraine and
some
some changes may occur soon possibly
possibly yeah
okay hey
so um
i had this video right but i think it's
it's uh i had answered a question last
week
about sebastian rabos
and i said that the question was mr bose
failed but why do we still admire him
and i had given an answer to that you
can look it up
it's available as a short clip on this
channel so uh so lots of people got
upset with that about that
they are all saying
so let's see what people are saying yeah
they
deep is saying why do you think he
failed kindly answered that it is so
wrong on so many levels to say that he
failed answer please
gator said he succeeded
the british lost no the battle was lost
but the war was won
without his contribution independence
day would certainly have been deferred
by a few years
bijoy says who said nitaji failed he
gives freedom to india
vijay says because of him we got
independence
the fear of azad in forge in the british
parish says netaji succeeded as india
got independence during the due to the
mutiny and so on
and the mera pete says correct yourself
fact is his idea and ultimates of
sacrifice
led to india's freedom in the late 1940s
all right
all right so everyone so lots of people
not everyone but lots of people are
saying that you that i am wrong mr bose
did not fail he gave india independence
and so on and so forth
okay
that's what you say now let's take a
look at this from a different
perspective
what were suwas chandra bose's
objectives
what were his stated objectives
he tried
being a politician
he was the president of the indian
national congress right in the the
congress party mr gandhi outmaneuvered
him
uh played a political coup against mr
bose and he was ejected he had to resign
right because he lost political support
that's the game mr gandhi played against
him
mohandas gandhi
so mr boss so
that when it comes to the car the indian
national congress they
did not support they they did not have
the same vision as mr bose had for india
they wanted cooperation with the british
they wanted uh
independence for india whenever it
happens on the terms set by the british
and the terms set by mr mr gandhi and mr
nehru
that's what the national congress was a
vehicle for it was a vehicle for the
eventual
transfer of power from the british to a
bunch of indians on the terms set by the
british which would include partition
and destruction of of india's
territorial integrity yeah
those though those
demands
for partition etc were already in the
air
at the time so mr bose decided to
dissociate himself from the congress
party he formed the forward block and
then he went into exile he escaped from
house arrest and his objective then
became to secure independence from the
british for india
through military means complete sampurna
swaraj
some stupid transfer of power on the
terms set by the british
no partition
a complete eraser
annihilation of all the harm the british
had done to india
yes what you these people are saying we
got independence
you call that independence it was a
transfer of power from one set of crooks
to another set of crooks
but the british interests remain in
india
you think
mr nero's prime minister was
independence for india do you think
that's that's independence
you think the 1946 uh
uh yeah we had a mutiny and all that but
that did not work right obviously
uh the constitution that india got you
think that is independence it is a
continuation of the of the 1935
legislation of the british the laws that
the british had written remained in
place the indian penal code dates back
to 1860 i think 1830 whatever it is look
it up
nothing changed
all the stooges the british had built up
over time in india
they retained their positions of power
and prestige after our so-called
independence
and the common people who had lost
everything
they still have nothing
before the riot act
ryot riot worry act that the british
legislated
almost all indians had some land
indians always had land
the british took it away and gave it
over to this i mean the process started
with the mughals with the turks
the zamindari system of uh
of taking away land from indians and
putting the the land in the in the hands
of these tax collectors and thugs called
zamindars and many indians were part of
that the so-called zamindars the tagores
tacos etc yeah
and the british took that further with
the rayatwari act and they
they took away all the ancestral land
from who from whatever was left of the
indian population
more than i don't know how many millions
hundreds of millions of indians had
their land usurped from them because of
this act so after independence
if it is real independence should the
land not be given back to indians
nothing of that happened
the same laws continued the same
institutions continued the people who
were in power their descendants are
still in power today in various indian
institutions
yeah
you do you really think that was
independence celebrating uh
some something on august 15th do you
think that is really real independence
the education system never changed we
are still being taught law of fake
history if mr boss had come to power he
would have stopped all that he would
have created a new system
he would have given you
some poorness
you are so blindfolded right now you
don't even realize that you are not free
right that is the problem
mr bose his objective was to give india
some poor naswaraj and to evict the
british
through force from india destroyed the
institutions of operation that they had
constructed
and recreate india from scratch
that's what his objectives were if miss
if you were to ask mr bose mr bose do
you think you succeeded or failed what
do you think he would say
mr bose was a man of standards
the problem with you all is that you
don't have standards unfortunately it's
sad to say this
if india is to i get this question every
day in the comments when will india
become a superpower do you think india
will become a superpower when you have
low standards
if you want india to become a superpower
raise your standards
raise your standards to the standards
that mr bose had for himself and then we
may have a chance with this attitude
with this attitude nothing is going to
change in india
if you were to ask mr bose he would be
the first to say that i failed in
achieving my objectives
yes it hastened india's so-called
transfer of power independence transfer
of power but what was the result of that
the results that he wanted have still
not materialized
so yes mr bose failed and if it
if it offends you so be it
okay
ask says the republic of india is a
continuation of british india face the
reality and stop spreading this
anti-white propaganda
no i agree
the republic of india is a continuation
of british india even today it's as if
the british are still ruling india
even today it is as if the british are
still ruling india i am speaking in the
language of the british the education
system is in the language of the british
you want a job you have to be able to
speak english you have a job you have to
go through through the grind of the
colonial education system yes in the
21st century they teach you computer
science and all that but the way they
teach things and the in the exams are
still the same as they were in the 19th
century nothing has changed it's about
memorization and about passing exams not
about actually learning anything
you're not allowed to question teachers
everything is the same the institutions
are the same
the constitution is a foreign
constitution it was drafted by this
constitution assembly that was the
result of the 1946 elections held by the
british on indian soil
a foreign occupying power held elections
how can you consider that to be
legitimate
less than 13 percent of eligible indians
were allowed to vote in the in those
elections if elections were held in
occupied france during nazi germany's
time do you think those elections would
be called legitimate but no
so yes
india is still colonized
and people don't realize it everything
is right in front of you but you don't
see it that's how blind people are so i
agree with my dear friend kill magnus
we have to face the reality india the
republic of india is a colonized nation
it is a continuation of british india
that thing has changed the laws are the
same the constitution is foreign
the indian penal code is the british
penal code
everything is the same the institutions
that you are laboring under
are british institutions
so i don't know what anti-white
propaganda you're talking about but i
agree with you
okay
says you always uh say that the bashing
leader khan abdullah khan was against
the partition but you seldom mentioned
the sindhi nationalist allah books
who lost his life in 1943 because he
stood against the lao resolution and the
partition of india uh yes you are right
i don't seldom mention him i have never
mentioned him until now
so yes allah was a sindhi
politician
he was an indian nationalist he was
dead set against partition he opposed
the partition vehemently
he was quite influential
and
yes he stood against the lower
resolution he opposed partition he
wanted a unified india he said that
muslims are indians they are not he he
opposed the two nation theory the komi
nazariyah yes and because of all these
things he lost he was assassinated in
1943 while while
being transported on a tanga
horse cart
yes
so yes there are many such people there
are not many such people but there are
some such people who deserve to be
remembered and recognized for putting
their lives in
everything on the line for the sake of
the
territorial integrity of india yes so uh
i would encourage my viewers if they are
interested
in reading more about this
this good man allah who was against the
partition of india and he had to pay the
ultimate price for that
erika says thank you thank you now the
question is
uh what was the special way of life and
governance that made india prosperous
before colonization and would it be
possible to live this way again today
we what would be required and how could
and everybody contribute to reach this
way of life also are there books about
this uh books
which address the specific issue i'm not
sure there are any
um
but let me address the main question
which is what was the special
way of life and governance that made
india prosperous before colonization
is it possible to live this way again
today see india is a river valley
civilization for 10 000 plus years india
has been in all in
settlements in the indian subcontinent
from top to bottom east to west north to
south have been
around river valleys so people talk
about the indus valley civilization that
is just one phase of india's
long history
we
if have
if you call that the indus valley
civilization there is a kaveri valley
civilization also there is a
valid civilization there is a ganga
valley civilization these are not
separate civilizations this is just
different local manifestations of the
overall
indian civilization so the first thing
is india has always been a river valley
civilization india has always been a
dharmic culture which worships nature
which
frowns upon any attempt to destroy
nature or exploit nature yes
killing of animals killing a forest
destroying forest all that was is
regarded as a sin right of course you
had warfare you had
meat eating at various times but it was
always done in a humane fashion warf and
the thing about this is that
see india as we know it's it's now known
that india was the nation with the
highest gdp in human history
for for the most part of human history
um the highest according to angus
madison is one third of the entire world
gdp well even those are
actually uh there are certain
oversimplifications in that and before
i think india's share of the world's gd
would have been higher than one half
maybe two thirds that's how prosperous
india was it was so widespread and so
extremely well developed we see that
even 5000 years ago you had better town
planning in india than what we have
today so india was technologically very
advanced but what are the
characteristics why did india become
this way
firstly
it's because
even when you had warfare the warfare
never targeted civilians in civilian
areas
the battles were always pitched there
would be a battlefield both sides would
fight there fight it out
and sometimes next to the battlefield
you would have farmers stealing their
crops and no
tilling their crops
and they would never be touched warfare
did happen
there were a few bad kings here and
there but overall warfare had certain
ethics ethical rules you would never
ever touch a civilian you never destroy
civilian property and therefore even
though various kingdoms from would from
time to time fight each other they would
divorce and they would be conquered by
other kings
india's economy would never ever suffer
and much of the wealth
was donated to temples temples were
educational institutions
kings would donate wealth the kids would
some kings and emperors would subsidize
education education was free healthcare
was free and there was a great deal of
prosperity there was always surplus
grains and all that to offset for el
nino kind of
events when you would have less rainfall
from time to time once in a while so
there were no famines in india so the
overall system
was such that whether you had a single
emperor who unified the whole
subcontinent or you had multiple kings
the the cultural aspect in the
civilization aspect was the same the way
of life was the same so when you had
conflicts you would never have
destruction of public property civilians
would never die it did not matter to
civilians who became the king
things would stay the same
and
the wealth of india
was built in a variety of ways first of
all you had natural resources yes
uh
india was the first
fully industrialized and urbanized
civilization in the known
history of the world yeah
so there was this emphasis on learning
on science and technology which of
course translates to military matters as
well and india had things that everybody
else wanted
india was trading with the chinese india
had the surplus grain production and all
others would want that in return india
would get gold india had extensive trade
with the greeks with the greek greece is
a small region but egypt was bigger and
rome was prosperous 2000 years ago so we
had ports in western india which would
send spices etc to the romans and the
romans would
send back gold to india in exchange for
that so because of this trade the india
had this enormous trade
surplus
with the world which is why india became
overtime over the centuries over the
millennium very prosperous india did not
have capitalism capitalism
means extremely rapid growth capitalism
is the endless pursuit of quarter upon
quarter profits
at the expense of everything else
and capitalism
is what is destroying the environment
today
the western world view is that the earth
is a resource
nature is a resource to be exploited
and that is causing the very rapid
destruction of our environment of the
oceans of the forests of the land
everything soil
india so nature and the earth is sacred
so whatever growth happened happened
slowly it happened over centuries
and the environment was never ever
destroyed
so that was the special thing about
india
the prosperity happened slowly
ten thousand years ago there would not
be so much gold and prosperity in india
i i imagine we don't know right we
because we have done no research from
the historical and archaeological
perspective from that time period
but we know that there there are cities
there are the remains of cities
that are under
the indian ocean
in the let's say the gulf of khambhat
that date back to 10 000 12 000 years
before today properly well designed
cities that date back 10 12 000 years
so india was that advanced archaeology
architecturally
and from an engineering perspective even
10 12 000 years before today so
so all the wealth that india
had
was acquired over centuries over
millennia it was slow
accrual of wealth it is so if you try to
recreate the same system today
it will take time
to reach the same levels of prosperity
maybe 200 years maybe 500 years
but the rest of the world follows
capitalism so that's why india is right
now
india has no option but to follow the
same practices as the rest of the world
is following but that is not good for
the environment and that's that's the
current drum that we are facing today
right so that is what what the uh
lifestyle was like that's how the kind
of governance we had
and that is what was destroyed by first
of all the turkic colonization and then
the western european and british
colonization of india that entire
lifestyle everything was totally
destroyed and all the wealth was
transported out of india
first by the turks and then by the
british they finished what the turks
started
nick says with such strong underpinnings
of hinduism which has taught us to be
strong and fight back when needed why
did we still fall short of defending
ourselves from external forces
i think there were times when india was
disunited it was fragmented
when whenever india has been unified
under a single emperor
whether it is during the mauryan era or
other eras then india has been
invincible
to unite india
this entire subcontinent-sized region
takes a great deal of fortitude
when you have emperors like that it is
impossible for people to even for
outsiders invaders to even think of
invading india you know alexander tried
you know what happened to him
and so on
so
it's not about hinduism
it's not about that it's about
india there were times when india was
not politically united under a single
central leadership vishnugov
said this
the highest duty or highest morality
of a king
is that his nation and his people should
prosper
right
only his nation
not other nations
so when you have an emperor like let's
say chandragupta maurya
like ashok or or like kaneshka or
rajendra or whatever
if they were able to unify a very large
portion of the subcontinent
it was their highest duty to ensure that
all the people within this region would
prosper and the nation would prosper
but if you had a time period when you
had disunity in india you had small
kingdoms then each king
would look out for his own people and
his own territory
at the expense of others obviously
because there is competition there is
rivalry
and during such times it is easy for
foreign powers to come and conquer you
and then occupy you and that's what
happened
during the turkic era during the era of
the turkic invasions first it was
invasions from the west from arabia they
destroyed persia first then they started
encroaching on western india balochistan
sindh gandhar afghanistan etc then you
had turkic invasions and these invasions
initially failed there were repulsed
time and again it took several centuries
for them to start encroaching into
mainland india
right
if you had
an emperor like chandragupta maurya or
ashok who was rather
nasty sometimes yeah or or kanishka etc
then such invasions would have failed
guaranteed but because india was
disunited even though some of these
kings and queens were very valorous etc
because there was a lack of political
unity that's why
india
eventually slowly over time fell to the
uh barbaric invasions from other places
which were indeed barbaric there is no
other way of putting it yeah
so that's what happened the the lesson
of the story
what is the moral of the story
you have to be united even today india
is not truly united there are lots of
forces within india that are pulling
india in different different directions
there are many forces within india i
have not taken any names by the way
there are many forces within india
whose interests
do not align
with the indian national interest their
agendas
are such that they are against india's
national interest there are so many such
forces
so
in such
circumstances you need a strong
government
you need political unity
and
yeah you need to deal with these things
so the moral of the story is you need
unity political unity and you need a
strong government and a strong military
which comes from a strong economy and of
course you need the right leadership you
may have the greatest military disposal
but if the leader is not quite
good
then you may still fail so you need a
combination of these factors in order to
uh
to prosper
all right
okay amansa says why do europeans
have no problems with indians but
extreme hatred towards the romani people
it's weird for me please answer and the
sibella who appears to be romani says
actually the roman law in turkey don't
speak romani and refuse to be
acknowledged as romani that's why they
are accepted by the turkish population
because they have all become muslim and
they have denounced the romani roots
okay let me answer the first question
first why do europeans have extreme
hatred for the romani people but they
have no problem with europeans
20 years ago the europeans would have
been quite racist against indians as
well
today
indians are all over the world they
contribute to the local economies indian
tourists go all over the world
india doesn't know this we in india
don't know it because we are not
encouraging tourism
when you have a massive influx of
tourists into your country it boosts
your economy
it boosts your economy at the grassroots
level
all the local shops in the city where
economy is happening
tourism is happening etc they prosper
and they welcome tourists
they may not like them but they will
keep the dislike hidden
and
they will show that you're all welcome
so that's why i always keep saying india
has the potential to become a tourism
superpower why don't we do it
it will make everybody prosperous so
when indians go to the western nations
european nations indians go there with
money and they spend the money
in in the touristic destinations
in cafes and restaurants and hotels and
shops
and that's why europeans have no problem
with indians coming there they like it
it makes them more prosperous it it
boosts their economy the romani
were refugees helpless refugees who were
expelled out of india they were taken as
slaves by the turks
into central asia
and then
they realized most likely there were so
many of these indian slaves that they
did not know what to do with them and
they didn't they most likely did not
they don't want to slaughter millions of
indians
on their own territory so then they sent
those indians who had take who had been
taken across the hindu kush mountains as
slaves men women children they sent them
best words they said you are not allowed
to go back to india get out of here go
westwards and don't come back here and
that was the terrible
tragic beginning of the romani story
the romani they speak a language that is
of western indian origin it is closest
to to sindhi gujarati and rajasthani
languages not to punjabi not to punjabi
there is a misconception that most
people have
you listen to the language you'll
actually understand words of it if you
understand any of the western indian
languages
so that's what happened the romanis came
as helpless
persecuted refugees and no one likes
helpless persecuted refugees who look
different who've got darker skin so the
romanians have been persecuted for the
past 1000 years in europe the europeans
hate them even today romani people are
still persecuted in europe they live
often in sub-human conditions and they
don't have human rights they don't have
documentation this is the crying shame
that europe still
it's a creation that the european
nations still do this
yeah
and you will see this in literature the
romanians have been executed for just
existing or they have been enslaved by
the europeans used as slaves
they've been auctioned off
even today many in many places they're
not allowed to live in cities or
sometimes that children are abducted and
forced to assimilate into european
society against their parent species all
kinds of horrible persecution has been
perpetrated and is still being
perpetrated on the indian origin romani
people
who are extremely talented people
spanish culture
is a gift given by the romanists to
spain flaming kurds flamingo music is of
romani origin
all right flamenco guitar flamenco dance
it's of romani origin which dates back
which can be traced back to india and so
many
uh great
sports people footballers
uh
boxers artists singers and so on
have been of romani origin right so that
that is the contribution of the romani
people to europe even though they have
been treated so badly now
sibila says
that the roman law many people in turkey
don't speak romani they refuse to be
acknowledged as romani and that's why
they are accepted by the by the turkish
population because they all became a
muslim and denounced the romani roots
there is
a significant amount of truth to what
sibella says
i believe
i don't have exact statistics in data
maybe the statistics don't exist but it
is rumored
people say this
that at least five percent of turkey's
population is of romani origin romani
ethnicity
yeah
and the deal is this in turkey if you
want to be
allowed to live in peace you have to say
that i am turkish i speak the turkish
language and i follow the local religion
and when people don't do this they face
persecution terrible persecution in
turkey look at what's happened to the
kurds
kurds mainly right
the kurds are not a turkic people they
are an indo-iranian people
and they they wish to have their own
nation and their self-determination and
all that and they have been persecuted
terribly by the turks look at what
happened to the armenians they're
christians
they are not a turkish people they have
their own language again persecution the
romani on the other hand have kept their
heads down they have kept a low profile
they say we are turkish we speak turkish
we we are muslims and so on and that's
why they are allowed to live in peace
everyone knows they are romani they look
different
you you go to istanbul
on the bosphorus
coast
and you see the flower cellars there etc
you will see some of them who look like
indians
they are indians i mean they are of
indian origin they're romani so the
turks know that romanis live among
our citizens of turkey as long as they
don't announce it that i am not turkish
i'm romani and all that they are allowed
to live in peace now let me give you an
interesting
historical anecdote um
you must have heard of the young turks
one second
so the young turks movement
is something that dates back to the
early 20th century in the final years of
the ottoman empire so there was this
young turks movement
which was a nationalistic movement which
wanted a progressive turkey
which wanted the end of the ottoman
empire to curtail the powers of the
ottoman sultan
and there were three leaders
and these guys did the genocide of the
armenians right they were
i mean they are to be blamed for that
now one of these guys
farad pasha
so talat pasha is is regarded as a war
criminal yes
he was
in a way the de facto leader of turkey
from 1913 to 1918.
take a look at what it looks like
this is what talat pasha looked like he
looks like an indian guy doesn't he
he was of romani origin
and he is he was a turkish turkish
nationalist
yeah that's what it is there are various
memes around him he's regarded by the
armenians as a war criminal by
historians as a war criminal as one of
the main architects of the armenian
genocide he was a turkish
nationalist and so on and so forth he
was assassinated by an armenian
so he was of romani origin
so as long as you
say that you're turkish and you when you
work for turkey and all that the turks
accept you so everyone knew that he was
a romani he looked different he he had
dark skin compared to the average
turkish person
and yeah he was a tall well-built person
and so on so that's one example a
tangible example of a romani person in
turkey and lots of turkish musicians are
of romani origin it's it's in lots of
turkish artisans who make handicrafts
etc
are of romani origin it's very well
known
okay rama lakshmi says why no
ramalakshmi says aren't strategic
bombers
high with high assets moving aerial
vehicles with low maneuverability than
normal jets okay aren't strategic
bombers similar to aircraft carriers
where they are quite there are many
similarities and threats to it
and tanks also weibo says what is the
role of bombers in any air force around
the world why are they so costly and why
doesn't india acquire bombers as only
russia china u.s have it now so let me
give you an example of what strategic
bombers look like
the americans have a number of strategic
bombers what are strategic bombers these
are
massive planes
some of them are subsonic some of them
are supersonic yeah
let's see strategic bombers
the one you're seeing right now is the
b1 bomber the bone
so there are various kinds of massive
planes this one is a supersonic plane
this is a different kind of plane the
what they have in common is they've got
very long range
they can fly
for maybe 10 000 kilometers with
refueling maybe without refueling and
they can carry massive amounts of
weapons bombs to be deployed
some of these so these are some future
strategic bombers apparently
uh the chinese are
investing in this the russians have
their tupolev
strategic bombers very long ranges
and we have the b2 the b2 bomber that
the americans have
the stealth bomber and so on and so
forth there are all these weapons and
weapon systems and uh aircraft under
development right
so what are the commonalities that
strategic bombers have
firstly a strategic bomber has a very
long range thousands of kilometers they
can fly most ideally without refueling
maybe 10 000 kilometers go far away do
your stuff and come back without
refueling secondly they can carry
massive amounts of bombs
so why the
why are strategic bombers needed
first of all
if you were to target
your na a target with cruise missiles so
if you want to destroy a target you can
send a bomber there and drop bombs on it
gps enabled bombs or whatever or you
could send cruise missiles that would
dissolve the target cruise missiles are
prohibited not prohibitively but very
expensive
cruise missiles typically costs
millions of dollars per piece per unit
you you you uh deploy
a hundred cruise missiles you're
spending more than 100 million dollars
but you could
drop many more bombs than that which
would achieve a much bet better effect
for you of destroying the target
for much less money
so that's why these strategic bombers
are useful for that
and strategy bombers are obviously
vulnerable like
rama lakshmi is saying
strategic bombers typically fly high
maybe 10 kilometers maybe 15 kilometers
and
they are visible they are slow moving
targets they are visible
so uh they face great threats nations
with good air defenses can take out
strategic bombers and that's why there
is nowadays the emphasis on stealth the
b2 bomber is a stealth bomber it's a
very long range bomber you can look up
the what range it has it can carry a
significant amount of
payload weapons payload bombs
and it's very hard to detect
but your other bombers like the b1
bomber etc they are visible and they can
be taken out with a nation with
reasonably good defenses there will be
counter measures that these aircraft
have so is is it true that strategic
bombers are similar to aircraft carriers
aircraft carriers are big slow moving
targets you can defend them with all
kinds of multi-layered defenses but it's
just a mathematical certainty that if
you have enough missiles you will take
out the aircraft carrier that's why
aircraft carriers are not used in
contested environments
aircraft carriers are never used in
contested
environments so what about these
strategic bombers are they useful so in
the past two three year decades where
have the americans
actually actively used
strategic bombers they have used
strategic bombers in places like kosovo
during the yugoslavia the balkan wars
of the the turn of the century in the
1990s
they have used strategic bombers in
afghanistan to target the taliban the
taliban can't shoot back
so it's okay
they've used strategic bombers in iraq
after they've destroyed all the air
defenses of saddam hussein they've used
strategic bombers in libya after
neutralizing air defenses they've used
strategic bombers in syria where again
the terrorists and assad's regime etc
are not terrorists the assad regime did
not have the ability to to take out
these bombers so the strategic bombers
today
are good at
carrying lots of bombs and carrying lots
of missiles over very large distances
and they are good at launching deploying
these these weapons on enemies that
cannot shoot back
yeah
if you were to send a strategic bomber
into contested airspace there is a very
high likelihood it will be destroyed
yeah so there are certain things that
strategic bombers do first of all they
they carry standoff weapons cruise
missiles that can be deployed at a long
range
so you come near the target maybe 1 000
kilometers or 1500 kilometers from the
target and then you launch a cruise
missile
so that is one kind of thing you could
do so the thing is that strategic
bombers are slowly but steadily becoming
obsolete unless you have something
that's invulnerable something like a
stealth bomber yeah
uh and strategic bombers can be replaced
by fighter planes
f-16s f-18s rafale jets stages jets that
can go and do the same thing and these
fighter planes can actually defend
themselves and destroy other aircraft as
well
but they cannot carry
a pages jet or a f-16 or a rafale cannot
carry thousands of tons of bombs so that
is a drawback
so either you use strategic bombers in
non-contested environments where there
is no chance of it getting destroyed or
you use very expensive cruise missiles
or you use fighter jets which need to
have multiple sorties
and
then they can carry less weapons and so
on so these are the various scenarios
that currently exist right so overall
war is expensive
yeah and there is always the possibility
that you will lose your expensive assets
and
increasingly strategic bombers are
uh slowly i would say getting uh
becoming obsolete in the future you will
have drones kamikaze drones
inexpensive kamikaze drones that could
perhaps do the thing or you could have
other kinds of
weaponry that do not put your
expensive platform at risk and your
people at risk yeah so yes i agree that
in in some ways a strategic bomber is
similar
to an aircraft carrier yeah
okay
donggar singh johann says u.s killed
that is a wiry in a couple drones strike
what's the evidence that he is dead
uh crazy brain says was taking down
zavahiri
and the announcement of the same before
pelosi's taiwan visit mere coincidence
yeah so to answer dungard since
question there is no evidence that he is
dead
they have shown no evidence we have to
believe their word
they said we have done this and we have
to they said we have killed him and we
here we have to just say okay the
american said it so it must be true
yeah
that's how it is they have given no
evidence that he is actually dead
similar to what they did with bin laden
they did not show any evidence of of him
actually being dead so we have to just
trust them
trust me i always tell the truth yeah
and
when it comes to the timing of the
announcement
before nancy pelosi's visit to taiwan
was it a coincidence it may or may not
have been a coincidence in geopolitics
there are actually no coincidences so
maybe it was timed in a manner that will
coincide with pelosi's visit
what was the purpose and the intent
behind it i'm not quite sure but
in a way
this uh they have chosen to kill
jawahar zawahiri
right now i am sure they have been they
have known where he has been for a very
long time
it seems they killed him in kabul
in the house of a guy who was a
contributor to the new york times or
something like that
so
i'm sure they were tracking him for a
very long time so why have they chosen
to kill him now and announce it now the
u.s is currently undergoing a massive
recession the economy is not doing well
people are unhappy uh there's a lot of
hardship the supermarkets are getting
becoming empty
all these internal issues so when people
are unhappy you throw them some crumbs
like this and make it look like yeah usa
usa usa us is great again
that could be the reason possibly and
even the pelosi visited taiwan to start
a new
new taiwan straight crisis could be
another diversion to divert the public
attention from the problems at home yeah
like i said
foreign policy is always a reflection of
the what is going on at home always in
any nation it's always a reflection of
that it's always
uh of uh you have to take those things
into factor into into account
okay let's take one more question
harry says how can i find
how can i find the courage to tell my
family about me being gay
they want me to say yes to a girl and
get married in the coming months but
they don't know about me
right right right right right right see
it's like this
um
you are what you are i i'm sure you know
that you are gay
and therefore it obviously does not make
sense for you to marry a girl you what
you're gonna if you do marry the girl
that is being proposed you're gonna end
up being unhappy yourself and you're
gonna end up making her also very
miserable
yes
you will not be happy and if you're not
happy she will also not be happy and
because you're gay she will obviously
realize that you are that so
it is not going to work out for you in
the long run you're going to be
miserable you're going to be unhappy
and we have to understand some some
basic things
all of us
what is the purpose of life
first of all the purpose of life is to
be happy and contented and secondly the
purpose of life is to contribute
something to society if you look at all
the historical figures big or small in
history who are remembered positively
and warmly it's because they have
contributed something big or small to
society they have given more than they
have taken in your immediate family in
your immediate social circle the people
who you like who you have warmth towards
they are people who give more than they
take
so i think it is the purpose of every
human life to find their own way in
which they can contribute something
meaningful and something positive to
society now if you are unhappy
if you are miserable
if you are conflicted internally if you
are conflicted externally
if you don't have a happy
personal life what will you contribute
to society
right
you think you think about that you don't
think about the long run if you
get married to this girl then
you will not have a happy life and you
will not contribute something good
anything good to society it will be very
hard for you to do that
and also remember this that it is not
your purpose in life it is not anyone's
purpose in life to please other people
your purpose in life is to contribute
something good
to
your immediate near and dear ones and to
society at large and you can't do that
by making compromises
that go against who you are
right
so uh i know it's tough
the first thing you have to do
is become financially independent when
you are financially independent you are
more confident and you are under
nobody's control that's the first thing
you do because you do
and then
you need to have openness in your
openness in your family i mean you have
when it comes to your immediate family
parents siblings etc there needs to be
openness that needs to be trust and you
need to be able to
express yourself and be who you truly
are without hiding anything
and if you are in an environment where
that doesn't happen if there is no the
the
where you are not loved unconditionally
then there is something wrong in that
situation
right
i mean
enough in a family you must have
unconditional love a person may be this
or that but we will love you no matter
what you are we will love you for who
you are that has to be there
so um
that
that is the i know that's the dilemma
you're facing you have to do what is
right you have to think of the long term
future not the immediate future
right now you may make a compromise
you may want to please your parents
and you will make a big sacrifice
personal occupation marry that girl but
what happens down the line
you will be unhappy she will be unhappy
and then slowly you will resent your
parents for forcing you to do this
and they will not even realize that you
made a sacrifice for them
so
it's unsustainable it's not going to
work that way
you
have to
stand up for yourself
and and do what's right you nee you must
tell them
yeah and maybe it may be difficult i'm
not i don't know what circumstances you
are in maybe you're not financially
independent so first you must become
financially independent and then you
have to do what is what is right for you
and right for everybody
right if there is if there is a lack of
openness and honesty then that's not a
functional family that's a disc
dysfunctional family
and
so yeah that's what i would say to you
do what is right don't marry a girl
don't ruin her life don't don't don't
make your life miserable
the hard
solution is the right solution for you
you must you need to find
the courage
to tell your parents that you are gay
and you do not wish to get married
and if they truly love you then they
will accept you for who you are right
so so
that's what i would suggest
i know it's it's difficult i know it's
scary
but
this is you standing up for yourself
right
if you respect yourself and if you want
to do something good in life you have to
get past this this hurdle and this
obstacle
so that's what i would say all the best
sir all the best
okay let's take a few questions from the
live chat
a few questions from the live chat if
you have questions
ask me now and i will take a few
okay let's say what let's see what we
have let's see let's see let's see
shaheen says what happened to
zoroastrians who migrated to china and
east asia
why only those who migrated to india are
still around today
well there must be some kind of
difference between india and china i do
know that there was some
small zoroastrian presence in china
even the munitions were there
and eventually it all died out
but as we know in india it's still there
so i'm not sure maybe the chinese were
not very receptive to foreign influences
and maybe the chinese ended that i am
not quite sure what the exact history is
because i've not studied that uh it's
it's in the overall big picture of
chinese history it's not that
significant unfortunately that's why
i've never even thought about this
question but what you are observing is
absolutely right zoroastrians did go
there was a zoroastrian presence small
presence in china maybe in east asia
also
and that did not survive at all
in india they're still around they are
less than a hundred thousand
zoroastrians in india but they are very
prosperous
uh if you are a zoro austrian i believe
i believe that if you are in in indian
zoroastrian and you earn less than 90
000 rupees a month that is the that is
that means that you are below the
poverty line so the zoroastrian poverty
line in india is 90 000 rupees a month
so that is something that most means
would regard as extremely
wealthy and prosperous but for them they
have a different
set of standards so that tells you that
zoroastrians have done very well in
india they have been treated very well
and they've been
um they've been given
the utmost respect and they have been
allowed to progress as far as they could
so that's the difference
that's how the difference has been
all right let us see
pratham says you once said that mustafa
kamala tatar was a true turkic
nationalist then why is turkey of assad
state of the us now did you know when he
died he died in 1938 i know i i think
if i am not mistaken he died in 1938.
today is 2022 it is not 1938.
a lot of water has flown under the
bridge since 1938.
so please study the history i cannot
tell you in three minutes what happened
yes
when he was alive turkey was nobody's
wasal state
he fought all the western powers and he
defeated them
then he died
he drank himself to death
he died of liver cirrhosis i believe
and then everything else happened
so if you want to understand why turkeys
where it is today please study the
turkish history post 1938
okay
turkey became essentially an autocracy
it was run essentially by the military
and then as this new power emerged on
the horizon this new global superpower
there was this cold war between the us
and the ussr and the turks
have always
had an antagonistic adversarial
relationship with russia which was now
the ussr and
because most likely of this historical
background they chose to side with the
us
and eventually the u.s became all
powerful in this region
and then slowly the turks became
a us was our state but they still have
imperial ambitions they still have the
ambitions today of restoring the old
ottoman iraq glory
all right so that is in brief what
happened i did say he was a true
nationalist but he died in 1938
please understand that today is not 1938
today is 2022
all right
uh who's ann
who's under trade
looks like i'm not very well informed i
don't know who andrew tate is
uh okay
let us see let us see let's see what
else do we have
uh
okay let's take this one
does china have territorial disputes
with nepal
right now there are no territorial
districts between china and nepal the
territorial disputes are between china
and bhutan between china and india and
between china and everybody else in the
universe but not nepal
the chinese are cultivating nepal right
now there is their objective
they want to turn nepal into a pro-china
chinese wasall state and use it against
india
until as long as it it has some value
when they are done with it they will
throw it to the wolves again yeah so the
chinese are cultivating nepalese
politicians
which was all started by the indian
government
in the 1990s
the
nepalese people had a monarchy it was a
monarchy that they had a hindu monarchy
it was the only hindu nation in the
world the indian government in the 1990s
supported the maoist terrorist
insurgency against the nepalese monarchy
royalty
we know what happened eventually
and now the this maoist communist
infiltration at all levels of nepalese
politics is playing into china's hands
so the chinese are playing very nice
with nepal they are supporting the
chinese the nepalese communist
politicians
and leaders
and they are ensuring there is no
territorial dispute as far as i know as
far as i know between china and nepal i
am sure there are certain issues they
will they will open when the time is
right
but there are issues with bhutan with
india we know even with pakistan and so
on
okay i think that should do it for today
we have crossed two hours as always so
thank you very much everybody today was
much more into geopolitics less of
history
but
we will redress that imbalance in future
episodes all right
thank you very much for all your
questions always always great to see
your questions and interact with you all
and i will see you in the next episode
until then take care be healthy
and
bye